thank you
[Music]
Google once upon a time in a great and
wild forest there lived the Spirit of
Hope
it was her duty to remind the forest
animals and humans of their Inner Light
the only cure for the great Darkness
the spirit fell in love with the fairy
King and gave birth to two beautiful
daughters with skin as dark as Walnut
ink and hair the color of Raven's
feathers
these daughters were named anger and
courage
you may think those names strange but in
fact they represented these daughters
well
anger was no shallow fairy spirit for
she was honorable she refused to accept
the darkness of the world as she found
it intolerable to live in misery like so
many humans who locked themselves away
and had forgotten how to love
[Music]
thank you
courage was also a noble creature and
was always inspired by anger to go out
into the forest and Beyond carrying the
light to the moon on our shoulders
spreading rays of peace and good dreams
to those who are willing to open the
shutters
hope soon realized that her life force
was bound to her daughters for together
they gave each other strength
with this knowledge she asked the noble
Fox spirits to protect her daughters by
watching over the wood
and if you ever find yourself wandering
in a forgotten corner of the wood you
may see them in the corner of your eye
and then you will know you are near to
Hope and that anger and courage are
there as well living in peace and
waiting to comfort those who wish to
heal
this story encapsulates so much about my
journey as a creative and this sentiment
of Hope and Magic is imbued in every
single piece of art I create be it
watercolors or poetry crafts or music
even more complicated feelings such as
anger and pain because I go to Art when
I feel these things
[Music]
I've always been a dreamer and someone
who has been ever perplexed by more
negative viewpoints of the world and its
inhabitants
people who wish to assume the worst of
others and often seem deeply unhappy
much like anger I couldn't understand
why someone might no longer see the
beauty of a dandelion growing on a
sidewalk or the gift of breath in their
lungs or the miracle of life itself
seeing life this way does not avoid
tragedy and struggle but it brings
sunsets and Imagination and noticing the
random acts of kindness all around you
it depends on your perspective but also
I think on Courage
art is all about recognizing both the
dark and light and creating paintings
utilizes these elements I find that the
practice of painting Fantastical
possibilities fill me with purpose and
reminds me of how we cannot Thrive
without dreaming without hope
and my art is a way that I remind people
that little simple things are as
important as the big ones
foreign
[Music]
I choose watercolors primarily when
creating art I never consistently paint
the real world and when I briefly took
College art classes I struggled to find
my place as I had a hard time forcing
myself to paint what I didn't find
interesting or inspiring
I was told that we had to compete in
order to have our art in a gallery
someday but from what I knew that was
going to be very unlikely for the woman
who liked painting fairy bunnies instead
I was going to accept this with Grace
and embrace a life of painting for
myself and letting my fairy tale
sensibilities guide my path
with great luck I was able to open a
shop and make a partial living for my
art and I still can't believe it
sometimes I tell my story not as a way
to put myself down or anyone who has
stayed within their comfort zone because
I'm proud and happy and at peace with
what I love to do and
there to my question of am I good enough
yes
because I'm creating what I love and
comparing my art with others is like
comparing two strangers life paths it
doesn't make sense
foreign
believer that there are many moments in
life where we need to push ourselves in
order to grow to step out and practice
discipline and embrace uncomfortable
feelings but not everything in life can
be that way we also need to have things
we simply like to do and do them not
worry about becoming the best or the
brightest I have been painting with
watercolors for as long as I can
remember and I've not been interested in
painting anything but fairies and
bunnies and wildflowers it's me and it's
enough and that is how I shine my light
and nurture hope for a brighter tomorrow
by imagining what wondrous things it
could be and knowing that I'm part of it
as are you
foreign
[Music]
I have tried to make it a goal of mine
this year to try to paint some more
because I don't always prioritize it and
yet it is so therapeutic for me I know
that especially when it comes to
creative things art but pretty much
anything in particular it can be quite
difficult for people to try new things
because they're afraid of not being good
at them that very thing inspired me this
week because I've always loved
watercolors and I encourage all of you
if you are thinking about trying to get
a little creative that this could be a
really good option it is one of the most
environmentally friendly options for
paint and something about the use of the
water and the brush Strokes is so
calming if you are able to let go of the
importance of the end result with
watercolors it's really about the
journey getting there when I've painted
with pastels or acrylics I often have a
lot of control over the pigments but
when it comes to watercolor it has a
little bit of its own spirit because the
water moves and dries in ways that you
would never expect and so I think the
very nature of this sort of painting is
what makes me attracted to it because
you never quite know what's going to
happen and it's a really good exercise
in letting go and accepting that the
water and the paint is kind of going to
do whatever it wants at the end of the
day you can only nudge it and encourage
it to go in certain directions well I am
working on a painting of a tree a very
Whimsical tree but it is based off of a
large oak tree that is near my home that
I visit quite often even though in real
life it doesn't look quite like this I
like to reimagine it and think about not
what things are but potentially what
they could be in another world I
remember being in school and being
surrounded by other artists and seeing
the incredible work that they could do
and admiring them so much I remember
thinking at the time the art that I
wanted to create didn't feel as
professional or impressive or something
that would demand respect compared to
the incredible murals and Architectural
and anatomical you know art that so many
artists were creating around me I
certainly didn't think that bunnies in
petticoats would be at all notable I did
find that I enjoyed it so much that I
just couldn't stand doing any other type
of art but what I loved and so I just
stuck to it and I accepted that I
realized how important it was to not
compare your art with other people in
the same way of just comparison in
general I think that's the easiest way
to lose all your passion and creativity
for what you do there will always be
someone out there that you might
perceive as more talented or more
successful and even if you make an
enormous achievement you didn't think
you could make if you have that mindset
of always comparing that achievement
won't mean as much or at least it won't
for the long term because soon you will
be only aware again of those who have
achieved something even greater and it
is a never-ending cycle and race to a
destination that I don't really know
what it is
speaking of someone who has been there I
do not know what the destination is of
constant comparison and chasing success
that mindset of scarcity of I'm not
enough I'm not good enough I'm not
talented enough I'm not going to achieve
enough then no matter what you
accomplish that mentality isn't just
going to go away overnight because it's
going to become your habitual way of
thinking and that was the case for me
for some time especially in University
which was a very competitive environment
for me so I'm deeply enjoying now
changing that pace changing that
mentality and I am so much more at peace
and so much prouder of my work now I did
finally create some new designs for my
Etsy Shop I've been meaning to for a
good month now so I did create this
magical oak tree as well as a little
squirrel painting so they were just some
simple designs but I greatly enjoyed
them because because they have been my
way to anticipate spring because we
still have so much snow on the ground
and I am so ready for the next phase of
the seasons oh my goodness I just cannot
wait but the sun is out today it is 40
degrees and I and feel like the end of
winter is on its way every day I'm
always just so warmed by how lovely and
kind people are I get to interact with
so many of you and it really means a lot
so I'm sending all of you my love have a
wonderful week and I will see you very
soon goodbye
[Music]
foreign